Based on truth and lies
Lords of Chaos is a drama, music, thriller film directed by Jonas Åkerlund.
A teenager's quest to launch Norwegian Black Metal in Oslo in
the 1990s results in a very violent outcome.
Øystein 'Euronymous' Aarseth, played by Rory Culkin.
Kristian 'Varg' Vikernes, played by Emory Cohen.
Pelle 'Dead' Ohlin, played by Jack Kilmer.
Ann-Marit, played by Sky Ferreira.
Bård Guldvik 'Faust' Eithun, played by Valter Skarsgård.
Jan Axel 'Hellhammer' Blomberg, played by Anthony De La Torre.
Lords of Chaos is a 2018 biographical horror film
directed and co-written by Jonas Åkerlund.
Adapted from the 1998 book of the same name, the film is a fictionalized account of the early 1990s Norwegian black metal scene
told from the perspective of musician Øysten “Euronymous” Aarsten who co-founded the influential group Mayhem.
The film stars Rory Culkin as Euronymous, Emory Cohen as Varg Vikernes, Jack
Kilmer as Per “Dead” Ohlin, and Sky Ferreira as Ann-Marit.
The film premiered at the Sundance Film Festival on 23 January 2018.
It was released in the United States on 8 February 2019 by Gunpowder & Sky, in the United Kingdom
on 29 March 2019 by Arrow Films and in Sweden on 5 April 2019 by Nordisk Film.
Critical reception for Lords of Chaos was mostly positive, but fans of metal music were
sharply polarized and the musicians depicted in the film had mixed feelings.
The film explores themes of suicide, based on novel or
book, nihilism, heavy metal, biography.
The tone is intense and dark and emotional.